RODRIGO DÍAZ SALVADORES

Product Design Engineer in Stockholm, Sweden

Forskarbacken 15, Stockholm · +34 633 019 977 · rodrigodiazsalvadores@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/rdsct

SKILLS

- UX/UI: User research (narration exercises, wire-framing, customer journey maps, competitor analysis), prototyping (Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch), graphic design (whole Adobe Suite).
- Programming: .NET (C#, XAML in WPF and UWP), web (HTML, CSS & JS).
- Industrial design: CAD (SolidWorks, CATIA V5, Alias), product visualization (Keyshot, Cinema 4D).

NICE TO MEET YOU!

I'm Rodrigo. I'm a recently graduated industrial design engineer at KTH in Stockholm. I have a strong passion for user-centered design in its many forms, in understanding user behavior and transforming it into something useful that hopefully creates an impact on people's lives. I have had the opportunity to show this in my more than five years of study and two years of experience at Thales Group.

EXPERIENCE

ELECTROLUX Stockholm, Sweden Student (Master Thesis) 01/2022 - Present

- I develop a user-friendly process for repairing stoves to fight early planned obsolescence.

- The project involves a deep analysis of product attachment and its role in product and industrial design.
- Achievements: team collaboration, multidisciplinary research, conceptual product development, prototyping and UX/UI design in Figma.

KTH (KUNGLIGA TEKNISKA HÖGSKOLAN)

Stockholm, Sweden

08/2021 - 12/2021

- I helped teach the Adobe Suite programs to 100 students in their first year at KTH.
- The students were able to learn sketching and product visualization with Adobe Photoshop.
- Achievements: a consequent improvement of the teaching quality and performance.

THALES GROUP Madrid, Spain .NET Developer 02/2019 - 08/2020

Teacher Assistant

- I created and developed specific programs for the railway division of Thales.
- Using Microsoft .NET with C# for the backend, and WPF for the UI and frontend, prototyping in Figma.
- Achievements: improved efficiency of tasks that were done by hand, digitalization of the department.

EDUCATION

KTH (KUNGLIGA TEKNISKA HÖGSKOLAN)

Master's Degree in Integrated Product Design (GPA: 3.2/4.0) 08/2020 - 06/2022

UNIVERSITY OF ALCALÁ DE HENARES

Master's degree in Decision Making and Innovation (GPA: 3.4/4.0) 09/2019 - 05/2020

POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY OF MADRID

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Design and Product Development (GPA: 3.0/4.0) 09/2015 - 05/2019

RELEVANT PROJECTS

ELECTROLUX Stockholm, Sweden

Master Thesis: The perfect DIY repair experience (Product Design)

01/2022 - Present

Stockholm, Sweden

Madrid, Spain

Madrid, Spain

- I designed a mobile app as the main pillar of a DIY repair experience for induction hobs, using Customer Journey Maps, user research and mockups with Figma.

PROJECT VERO Stockholm, Sweden

AR Glasses for a better online education (Service Design)

08/2020 - 01/2021

- I developed a service based on AR glasses that would enhance both student's and teacher's experience during the pandemic. See them in action here.